Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956. Letters to Reginald Turner (bMS Eng 1098): Guide.
Letters to Reginald Turner,
1892-1938.
Houghton Library, Harvard College Library, Harvard University
MS Eng 1098
Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956.
3 boxes and 1 v. (1.6 linear ft.)
Letters of British author and caricaturist Max Beerbohm to British author Reginald Turner, largely on personal matters.
*58M-179
Purchased by the Friends of the Library from Tania Jepson, 10, Orme Square, London W. 2; received: 1959 April 15.
Beerbohm was a British author and caricaturist. Turner was a British author.
Arranged chronologically.
Consists of 221 letters from Beerbohm to Turner, a few with drawings, largely about personal matters.
- Beerbohm, Sir Max, 1872-1956. 214 letters to Reginald Turner:
  - [Merton College, Oxford, 14? Oct. 1892], (1); 4s.(15p.)
  - [ London, Early Sept. 1892], (2); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, Sept. 1892], (3); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, Sept. 1892], (4); 1s.(3p.)
  - [Myrmidon Club, Oxford, Oct.? 1892], (5); 1s.(2p.)
  - [London, Early July1892]., (6); 2s.(2p.)
    Typed copy of (213b).
  - Merton College, Oxford [3 Mar 1893], (7); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [London, 12 Apr 1893], (8); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [Same, 15 Apr 1893], (9); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 21 Apr 1893], (10); 2s.(8p.)
  - Merton College, Oxford [25 Apr 1893], (11); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same [7 May 1893], (12); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same [13 May 1893], (13); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - Same [15 May 1893], (14); 2s.(7p.) env.
  - [London, 10 Jul 1893], (15); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, Jul 1893], (16); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, 20 Jul 1893], (17); 1s.(2p.) env.,
    Pass enclosed.
  - [Same, Early Sept. 1893], (18); 3s.(11p.)
  - Broadstairs [Sept. 1893], (19); 2s.(8p.)
  - [London, 9 Aug 1893], (20); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [Same, 10 Aug 1893], (21); 4s.(12p.) env.
  - [Same, 13 Aug 1893], (22); 3s.(12p.) env.
  - [Same, 14 Aug 1893], (23); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 15 Aug 1893], (24); 3s.(11p.) env.
  - [Same, 19 Aug 1893], (25); 4s.(16p.) env.
  - [Same, 21 Aug 1893], (26); 3s.(12p.) env.
  - [Same, 24 Aug 1893], (27); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 25 Aug 1893], (28); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, late Aug 1893], (29); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 17 Sep 1893], (30); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 19 Sep 1893], (31); 3s.(10p.) env.,
    drawing of Cissie Loftus.
  - [Same, 21 Sep 1893], (32); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 22 Sep 1893], (33); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [Same, 24 Sep 1893], (34); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 29 Sep 1893], (35); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 2 Oct 1893], (36); 2s.(7p.) env.
  - [Same, 13 Oct 1893], (37); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 14 Oct 1893], (38); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [Same, 16 Oct 1893], (39); 3s.(10p.) env.
  - [Same, 21 Oct 1893], (40); 2s.(8p.) env.,
    drawing of Cissie Loftus and Max Beerbohm.
  - [Same, 3 Dec 1893], (41); 1s.(1p.)
    Typed copy of item (213c).
  - Moreland House, Tunbridge Wells [19 Dec 1892], (42); 2s.(7p.) env.
  - Same [Early Jan. 1893], (43); 1s.(3p.)
  - Oxford [1893?], (44); 1s.(2p.)
  - [London, Late June 1892], (45); 1s.(1p.)
    Typed copy of item (213a).
  - Hotel des Pays Bas, Spa [20 Aug. 1891], (46); 1s.(3p.) env.,
    drawing of Turner and Beerbohm.
  - Merton College, Oxford [25 Feb. 1893], (47); 2s.(5p.)
  - Same [21 Feb 1894], (48); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [London, 19 Dec. 1893], (49); 1s.(2p.)
    Typed copy of item (213d).
  - Oxford [8 Mar 1894], (50); 3s.(12p.)
  - [London 16 Mar 1894], (51); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 24 Apr 1894], (52); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 7 Aug 1894], (53); 3s.(12p.) env.
  - New York [22 Feb 1895], (54); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - Chicago [3] Mar 1895., (55); 3s.(9p.) env.
  - [London, 3 May 1895], (56); 3s.(10p.) env.
  - [Same, 15 Jul 1895], (57); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - King's Lynn [13 Aug 1896], (58); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London, 7] Sep 1896., (59); 1s.(1p.)
  - [Same, 21] Sept. 1896., (60); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same] 29 Sep 1896., (61); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 9 Oct 1896], (62); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - [Same] 13 Oct 1896., (63); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - [Same, 14] Oct [1896], (64); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Bognor, 5 Nov 1896., (65); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same [2? Apr. 1896], (66); 1s.(3p.)
  - Same, 8 Nov 1896., (67); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [London] 10 Nov 1896., (68); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - [Same, 24 Dec 1896], (69); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Ca. 8 Nov. 1897], (70); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, 1896?], (71); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, Dec.? 1897], (72); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, 1896], (73); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, 8 Jan 1897], (74); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - [Same, 12 Jan 1897], (75); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - Windermere, [18 Apr] 1897., (76); 1s.(1p.)
    Typed copy of item (213e).
  - Folkestone [16 May] 1897., (77); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London] 31 May 1897., (78); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - Bognor [20] Aug 1897., (79); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - Same [early Aug 1896], (80); 2s.(8p.)
  - Same [5] Sep 1897., (81); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London] 30 Nov 1897., (82); 1s.(3p.)
  - Ferry Hill, [12] Jan 1898., (83); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - Folkestone [31 Jan 1898], (84); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London, ?Apr.-May 1896], (85); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 4 May 1898], (86); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [Same] 24 May 1898., (87); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [Same, 26 May 1898], (88); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [Same, 17 Jun 1898], (89); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [Same, 27 Jun 1898], (90); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Cowes, 23 Aug 1898., (91); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [London, 20 Oct 1898], (92); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Boulogne, Late Sept. 1897], (93); 1s.(2p.)
  - [London] 21 Nov 1900., (94); 1s.(4p.) env.,
    clipping.
  - [Same, 1 Dec 1900., (95); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Brighton [11 Dec] 1900., (96); 3s.(11p.) env.
  - [London, 24 Dec 1900], (97); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same] 1 Feb 1901., (98); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 10 Jun 1901], (99); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 22 Jul 1901], (100); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Dieppe, 30 Jul 1901], (101); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - Same, [5 Sep 1901], (102); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [London, 4 Dec 1901], (103); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [London] 20 Jan 1903., (104); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 16 Apr. 1903], (105); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 24 Apr 1903], (106); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 8 May 1903], (107); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [Same, 23 May 1903], (108); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [Same] 25 May 1903., (109); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 4] Jun 1903., (110); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 10 Jul 1903], (111); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 11 Jul 1903], (112); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 13 Jul 1903], (113); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 8 Jul 1903], (114); 2s.(7p.) env.
  - [Same, 9 Nov 1903], (115); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 30 Dec 1903], (116); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - Tribunaux [1 Sept. 1903], (117); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [London, 16 Mar 1904], (118); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same] 12 Apr 1904., (119); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [Same, 13 Apr 1904], (120); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [Same, 21 Apr 1904], (121); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Verona [8 Oct 1906], (122); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London, 8 Nov 1909], (123); 1s.(1p.)
    Typed copy of item (213g).
  - [Same] 14 Feb 1906., (124); 1s.(4p.) env.,
  - [Same, 28 Apr 1906], (125); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 10 Jun 1906], (126); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Andover [23 Jul 1906], (127); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - [London] 8 Sep 1906., (128); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 20 Sep 1906], (129); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 20 Sep 1906], (130); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Florence [14 Oct 1906], (131); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London, 21 Oct 1906?], (132); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 30 Oct 1906], (133); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 9 Nov 1906], (134); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 23 Jul 1903], (135); 1s.(3p.)
  - Portofino, 26 Nov 1907., (136); 2s.(2p.)
    Typed copy of item (213f).
  - [London, 8 Apr 1908], (137); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same] 22 Dec 1908., (138); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same] 23 Dec 1908., (139); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 8 Oct 1909], (140); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same, 22 Nov 1909], (141); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 1909?], (142); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Paris [7 Feb 1910], (143); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London, 18 Feb 1910], (144); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same] 15 Apr 1910., (145); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 18 Apr 1910], (146); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - Hythe [15 May 1910], (147); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Santa Margherita, 24 Jun 1910., (148); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Rapallo [21] Aug 1910., (149); 2s.(4p.) env.,
    drawings of Rapallo.
  - Same [15 Nov 1910], (150); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - Same, 22 Dec 1910., (151); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 20 June 1921., (152); 4s.(4p.)
    Typed copy of item (213h).
  - Rapallo [15 Feb 1911], (152a); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [London, 20 Apr 1911], (153); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - [Same, 21 Apr 1911], (154); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, 22 Apr 1911], (155); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 22 Apr 1911], (156); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Rapallo [25 Apr 1911], (157); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same [10 May 1911], (158); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Venice [25 May 1911], (159); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - Rapallo, 10 Jul 1911., (160); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same [2 Oct 1911], (161); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - Same [7 Oct 1911], (162); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 24 Oct 1911., (163); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 3 Nov 1911., (164); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - Same [6 Dec 1911], (165); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - [London, 15 Apr. 1913], (166); 1s.(2p.)
  - [Same, 19 Apr. 1911], (167); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Rapallo [25 Feb 1912], (168); 1s.(2p.) postcard.
  - Same [31 Mar 1912], (169); 1s.(1p.) postcard.
  - Same [2 Apr 1912], (170); 1s.(1p.) postcard.
  - Same [27 Jul 1912], (171); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [London, 8 Nov 1912], (172); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same] 14 Nov 1912., (173); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - [Same, 20 Nov 1912], (174); 1s.(3p.) env.
  - [Same] 23 Dec 1912., (175); 2s.(6p.) env.,
    drawing of Bonar Law.
  - [Same, 23 Jan 1913], (176); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Rapallo [22 Apr 1913], (177); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - Same [11 Mar 1913], (178); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same [3 Jun 1913], (179); 2s.(8p.) env.
  - Same [8] Oct 1913., (180); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 14 Apr 1914., (181); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, [27 Apr 1914], (182); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same, 6 Sep 1914., (183); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - Same [27 Dec 1914], (184); 1s.(4p.)
  - [Same, 5 Jan 1915], (185); 1s.(2p.) postcard.
  - Same [19 Jan 1915], (186); 1s.(4p.) env.
  - Same [25 Feb 1915], (187); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - Same, 18 May 1920., (188); 7f.(14p.) env.,
    drawing of A.J.Balfour and R. Turner.
  - Same, 10 Jul 1920., (189); 5f.(10p.)
  - Same [20 Feb 1920], (190); 2s.(6p.) env.
  - Same, 22 Dec 1920., (191); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same [1920?], (192); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - Same [1920?], (193); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same, 10 Apr 1926., (194); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same, 11 Apr 1926., (195); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same, 29 Mar 1926., (196); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same [4] May 1927., (197); 2s.(3p.) env.
  - Same, 2 Oct 1927., (198); 3s.(6p.) env.,
    including A.L.s. of Florence (Kahn) Beerbohm, and drawings of Keir Hardie and Alfred Lambart.
  - Same, 14 Oct 1927., (199); 1s.(1p.)
    Typed copy of item (213i).
  - [Same] 17 Oct [1927], (200); 1s.(2p.) postcard.
  - Same [1 Feb 1928], (201); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 22 Feb 1928., (202); 1s.(2p.) env.,
  - [London] 21 Jul 1930., (203); 3s.(5p.) env.
  - Rapallo, 27 Aug 1935., (204); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - London, 7 Sep 1935., (205); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 30 Sep 1935., (206); 2s.(4p.) env.
  - Same, 2 Oct 1935., (207); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Rapallo, 24 Mar 1936., (208); 1s.(1p.) env.
  - [London, 16 Apr 1936], (209); 1s.(2p.) postcard.
  - Rapallo, 18 Nov 1937., (210); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - Same, 3 Mar 1938., (211); 1s.(2p.) env.
  - [London, 18 Nov 1938], (212); 3s.(6p.) env.
  - Formerly restricted letters., (213a - 213i); 1 folder.
    These nine letters were restricted until Jan. 1984. Typed excerpts from 8 of these letters are listed above as nos. 6, 41, 45, 49, 76, 123, 136, 152, 199.
    Includes the following letters:
    (213a) 19, Hyde Park Place, W., London, [late June 1892] 1s. (4p.) See also item (45).
    (213b) 19, Hyde Park Place, W., London, [Late June 1892] 1s. (4p.) See also item (6).
    (213c) 19 Hyde Park Place, London, [3 Dec. 1893] 1s. (4p.) env. See also item (41).
    (213d) 19 Hyde Park Place, London, [19 Dec. 1893] 3s. (12p.) env. See also item (49).
    (213e) St. Mary's Abbey, Windermere, Easter Sunday, [18 Apr.] 1897. 1s. (4p.) env. See also item (76).
    (213f) Castell San Giorgio, Portofino, Liguria, 26 Nov. 1907. 1s. (2p.) env. See also item (136).
    (213g) 48 Upper Berkeley Street, W., [8 Nov. 1909] 1s. (4p.) env. See also item (123).
    (213h) Villino Chiaro, Rapallo, 20 June 1921. 2s. (4p.) env. See also item (152).
    (213i) Villino Chiaro, Rapallo, 14 Oct. 1927. 2s. (4p.) env. See also item (199).
- Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956. Letters to Reggie Turner, edited by Rupert Hart-Davis: proofs with AMs annotations by William H. Bond, 1964., (214); 1 v.
  This volume serves as a concordance between the Houghton collection item numbers of the Beerbohm letters and the listing in the published work.